The Life Of Muhammadﷺ, The Makkan Period
By Imam Anwar Al-Awlaki
اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرا
This is our third session.
In Sha Allah(ان شاءالله) we will talk about the religious background of Arabia,
so that we know the environment in which Rasool Allah ﷺ lived.
Now, obviously they started on Touheed(توحيد) because of the Da'wah(دعوة) of Ismail عليه السّلام.
He was their Prophet, and they followed him.
So, the Arabs of Arabia started out as Muslims as believers in the oneness of Allah.
So, what went wrong, down the line for them to reach to the level they were at,
when Rasool Allah ﷺ was sent to them.
In the time of Rasool Allah ﷺ there were three religions in Arabia,
idol worshipping, Christianity and Judaism.
So, we'll talk about how these three religions came into existence.?
Amr Bin Lohae Al-Khuza'e(عمرو بن لوحي الخزاعي),
you remember him, he is the leader of Khuza'a(خزاعه).
This man was very generous, very strong, very much respected by his people.
They used to respect him so much, and admire him, so much that his words were taken as law.
كَانَ قَوْلَهُ يُوْخَذْ كَشَرْعَ
Amr Bin Lohae Al-Khuza'e(عمرو بن لوحي الخزاعي), he traveled to Syria, to Ash-sham(الشام).
And I'm translating Ash-sham(الشام) as Syria, even though it's not the correct translation,
I mean Ash-sham(الشام) refers to Syria, Phalastine(فلسطين), Lebanon(لبنان) and Jordan.
That land is called Ash-sham(الشام).
And the center of Ash-sham(الشام) is Jerusalem, Bait-Ul-Maqdis(بيت المقدس).
But it has been translated in English and Syria, so we'll just go by that translation, for now.
So, here we have Amr Bin Lohae Al-Khuza'e(عمرو بن لوحي الخزاعي), he is traveling to Ash-sham(الشام) to Syria.
He goes there, and he finds these idols, so he asked the people,
What are these.?
So, they told him: Well, these are intermediates between us and Allah.
يُقَرِّبُوْنَ اِلَى اللهِ زُلْفَى
So, when want to ask for rain, we asked them, they appeal on our behalf to Allah.
When we want children, we would go to different idol,
when we want this, you'd go to that idol, in war we have a certain idol.
And they appeal on our behalf to God and they perform things for us.
Amr Bin Lohae (عمرو بن لوحي) said: Excellent, this is what we need.!
That is what we need, we need someone to appeal to our Lord to provide us with rain, to provide us with wealth.
How about, you hand me over one of these idols, so I can take it back home.
So, they gave him a pretty good idol, big huge called Hubal(حُبَلْ).
So, he carried Hubal(حُبَلْ) with him back to Makkah.
And he established it, next to Al-Ka'aba(الكعبه), in Al-Haram(الحرم).
And he told his people, these will intercede on your behalf to Allahسبحانه وتعالى, ask them whatever you want.
Now, Makkah being the center of Arabia the religious authority of Arabia,
bringing an idol to Makkah carried with it, such a heavy weight, I mean
you have the Arabs coming from all over the peninsula to make Hajj(حج).
So, all of them were exposed to this new Bid'dah(بدعة), innovation in religion.
And it started spreading like wildfire.
Because it was coming from the religious center.
And it was also adopted by Amr Bin Lohae Al-Khuza'e(عمرو بن لوحي الخزاعي), who was so respected by his people.
So now, it became a business, in Makkah they would make idols to export to the other tribes.
So now, every tribe would come to Makkah and they would carry with them an idol to take home,
because they cannot come all the time and ask from Hubal(حُبَلْ).
So, they would have these idols that they would carry with them.
And then this concept was developed further, I mean, it starts out small and then it grows.
The concept was carried further, so now they were making portable idols,
you carry it in your backpack wherever, you're traveling you have one with you.
I don't know, if you remember the story of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب).
He was one seen crying and laughing,
so he was asked:
Why were you crying and why were you laughing.?
He said the reason why I was laughing is.
I remembered in the time of Jahilliyah(جاهليه), in the time of ignorance.
I was traveling, and I wanted to pray.
But then I remember that I forgot to bring my god with me.
So, what I did is, I tried to think of a way, I want to pray.
So, I had some dates with me.
So I molded the dates into a form of an idol,
and I worshiped it.
Later on, that night I became hungry.
So, I ate my idol.
He said, that's why I'm laughing.
You know, now he's looking back and he is saying, what was I doing, how could I do that.?
You see how Islam changed, see how Islam changed them.
See, who was Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) and who he became after Islam.
You know, these giants Sahabah(صحابه), when you read about them and their wisdom, this is where they were.
So, this shows you how Islam had the power to change them from being nothing, to being the best,
how Islam transformed them in a very short period, that's a miracle.
That's a miracle of Islam that it had the capacity to bring such a people,
and to bring about in their lives such a change, and make out of them, these giants.
I mean Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), who would Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) be without Islam.?
Abbas Mahmood Al-Aqqaad(عباس محمود ألعقاد), he asked that question,
in his book about Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب), he says,
who would Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) be without Islam.
He said: Maybe he could grow to become the leader of his clan,
his family of Bannu Udae(بنوعُدَيْ) which were a very small branch of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
He said, or maybe he could have been one of the prominent leaders of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
Or if we extend it further than he might be the head of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
which is a farfetched assumption because the other clans of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
who held power in the past, would never allow such a thing to happen, to start with.
So, he said, we're stretching it too far to say that he would become a leader over Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
He said: But the most likely scenario was that Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) would die at a young age,
he used to drink a lot before Islam.
So, most likely he would have died at a young age,
and Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) would have been an obscure figure of history.
But with Islam,
not only he become a leader of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
or Arabia, he became the ruler of two thirds of the world at that time.
One of the greatest men that ever lived in history.
That is the transformation that Islam brought in their lives.
Anyway, so idols were being exported
and now they were being made in different shapes and forms and you have a different idol for a different purpose
and Al-Ka'aba(الكعبه) was polluted, surrounded with idols.
Three HUndred and sixty(360) idols surrounding Al-Ka'aba(الكعبه).
Shirk(شرك) now was in every direction,
What started out as one idol imported turned into a huge exporting business
and Shirk(شرك) it in every direction in Makkah.
So, that is how the religion of Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) changed down the line.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
رَاَيْتُ عَمْرو بِنْ لُحَئ اَلْخُزَاعِي، يَجُّرُّ قُصْبَه’ فِيْ النَّارْ
كَانَ اَوَّلَّ مَن بَدَّلَ دِيْنَ الْعَرَبْ
Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
I have seen Amr Bin Lohae Al-Khuza'e(عمرو بن لوحي الخزاعي) dragging his entrails, his intestines in hellfire,
because he was the first man to change the religion of the Arabs.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ said: I saw him in Hellfire, going around his intestines trying to pull them back in his stomach.
So, this is how idol worshipping was introduced in Arabia.
What about the Jewish faith and Christianity.?
The King of Yemen, Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) was traveling to do business in Ash-sham(الشام).
And he passed next to Al-Madina,
and he left his son in Madina to do business, until he comes back from Syria.
The people of Madina killed his son.
So, when Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) came back and heard the news that his son was killed.
He decided to destroy Madina.
So, he attacked and his army was overwhelming, compared to the small armies of Madina,
so he could have crushed, his opposition.
But two Jewish rabbis came out of Madina.
Now how did Jews get there in the first place.?
When the Romans destroyed Jerusalem,
the Jews dispersed,
there were some of them, who came down into Arabia.
In search of the promised land where the Nabbi(نبي) would be sent.
Because they had in their books signs of the awaited prophet.
So, they were looking for the place where he would immigrate to.
They saw these signs in Madina and in a few other places, in Hajar(حجر), and other places.
So, and this is where the Jews settled.
Because these places, had the resemblances or the signs of the place where the Prophet would be sent.
So, that is why they settled in Madina.
Three Jewish tribes, we had Bannu Qainuqah(بنو قَینُقاع), Bannu Nadhir(ببنو نضير) and Bannu Quraidha(بنو قريظه).
So, that's how they reached Madina, so they were ethnically Jewish,
who emigrated when the Romans sacked Jerusalem.
So, these two Jewish rabbis they came out,
and they came to Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) and they told him,
This place is protected by God, if you attempt to destroy it, Allah will destroy you.
And they were able to convince Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ).
Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) not only agreed to withdraw his army and stop attacking Madina,
but he also was impressed by their religion
and wanted to become Jewish himself.
And then he invited these two Jewish rabbis to go with him to Yemen,
and they agreed, and he became Jewish.
Now, on his way south, heading back to Yemen.
The tribe of Hawazin(هوازن), they had a problem between them and Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
Hawazin(هوازن), they had a problem with the people of Makkah.
So, they wanted to make a Fitnah(فِتْنَه) to start a division or cause a problem
between Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) and Makkah and they succeeded.
So, Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) was contemplating attacking Makkah.
Now these two Jewish rabbis told him,
This is another town that is protected by Allah,
you shouldn't attack Makkah, in fact, he should go into Makkah and make Tawwaf(طواف) around Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
He said: Well, let's go.
They said: No, we cannot join you.
How come.?
They said: We are scholars and it is not appropriate for us,
as scholars to go and make Tawwaf(طواف) around Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه), when it's surrounded by Idols.
So, he went in and he made Tawwaf(طواف),
and the Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) was the first person ever to cloth Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
He was the first one to clothe Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
And he would cloth it, once a year.
And the way they would do it in the past is.?
They would bring the new clothing and place it over the old,
because they considered, the clothing of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) to be sacred and they can take it off.
So, they would keep on piling up one cloth over another, until the sheer weight of it was so heavy.
Eventually they decided that they're going to have to take it off,
and just place one clothing at a time.
Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) then went with these two Jewish rabbis to Yemen and they were given freedom
and encouragement to spread the religion, among the Yemeni tribes.
And many of the tribes in Yemen did embrace the Jewish faith.
So, you have two types of Jews in Arabia.
You have ethnic Jews in Khaybar(خيبر) and Madina
but then you have Jews by conversion, in Yemen.
So, the Jews of Yemen, are ethnically Arab, but they adopted the Jewish faith.
So, you can see that at some moments of time, Jews did preach their religion,
and now they might not do that but there were points in history where they did, preach their religion to others,
and an example is, Yemen.
So, that's how the Jewish religion was introduced into Arabia.
What about Christianity.?
When Eesa عليه السّلام was sent some of his followers dispersed in the land
and Christianity was dividing into many sects very early on.
And very early on, many of these sects became disbelievers.
They were Dhalah(ضلاله), misguidance was introduced very early on into the sects of Christianity.
However, there were pockets of believers here and there that were able to retain the true Christian faith,
that was preached by Syedina Eesa(سيدناعيسى), Jesus عليه السّلام,
believing in the oneness of Allah, believing that Eesa(عيسى) is as a messenger of Allah, rather than being the son of God.
These were concepts that were retained by some of the Christians around the world.
One of these men made it into Yemen,
and started preaching in the area of Najraan(نجران).
And their religion was spreading but secretly and privately and slowly.
By that time Tabbana Sa'ad(تَبَّانَه سَعْدْ) was dead.
And the king of Yemen was his son, Abu Nawaas(ابو نواس) or Du Nawaas(ذو نواس).
News of this new religion reached to the king, and he banned it, and he persecuted the followers.
There is the story in Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم) of the king, and the young boy.
Many scholars would attribute this story to the events between Du Nawwas(ذو نواس) and the Christians in Yemen,
it would say that the king was Du Nawwas(ذو نواس),
and that story is in Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم) we will go over it.
It says that the king used to deal in magic.
And he had the sorcerer as his advisor.
So, this sorcerer was growing old in age,
and he told the king that I might pass away in any moment so I need to train someone, to take my place.
I need to inherit my skills to someone, who would carry on.
So, they tried to find the very bright and intelligent young man and they handpicked a young man
and they assigned him as an apprentice with this sorcerer.
So, he was supposed to leave very early on, in the morning
from his house and go and study under the sorcerer, and then come back home at night.
Now this young man on his way towards the Saahir(ساحر), the sorcerer, saw a worship place.
And he heard prayers coming in from this place, which were different.
So, he decided to go and visit.
And it was a church of Tauheed(توحيد) of unity of Allah, preaching the true religion of Eesa عليه السلام.
And he was very impressed by what he was hearing.
But he's supposed to be studying with the sorcerer.
So, he asked the priest, he told him: What can I do?
The priests told him, when you leave home visit me and come and study with me
and then go to the sorcerer and if he tells you how come you were late.
Tell him, because my parents delayed me.
On your way back visit me.
And when you get home, when your parents tell you how come you're late tell them that the sorcerer delayed me.
So, you could take a class in the morning and take a class at evening.
So, he continued doing that for a while.
One day in the market place.
Certain beasts entered into the market place and cause chaos, among the people and no one was able to deal with it.
So, this young man said:
O Allah, today I want to know whether the path of the priest or the path of the sorcerer is the truth.
So, O Allah, show me the truth.
And everyone was attempting to kill this beast and no one succeeded.
And then this boy picked up a rock and he said:
O Allah! If the path of the priest is the truth, then kill this animal.
And he threw the rock, and it killed the animal immediately.
He went back and reported this to the priest, he told him what happened.!
The priest told him, my son, today you have achieved, attained a very high status.
Therefore, you would be tested,
you will go through trials,
no one can reach such a high status without being tested by Allah.
In exams, the better the student, the more difficult the exam should be.
Because you want to tell the difference between the levels of the students.
So, you have easy questions, which everyone is able to answer.
And then you have medium difficulty.
And then you have difficult and then you have very difficult,
because you want to distinguish the A plus, from A minus.
You want to tell the difference.
Same thing Allahسبحانه وتعالى has brought us on this earth for a test.
And according to your level, you would be tested.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
اَشَدِّالنَّاسْ بَلَادْ اَلْاَنْبِيَآءْ، فَالْاَمْثَلْ فَالْاَمْثَلْ
The ones, who go through the most difficult tests are the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء).
And then it goes down according to your level.
So, this priest was telling the young man, you will be tested.
And then he told him and when you are tested, do not disclose my name.
Because the priest was doing his Da'wah(دعوة) in secret.
And he doesn't want his name to be exposed.
It is not out of fear, this is for the security of the Da'wah(دعوة).
So, he told him, and when you go through trials, do not mention my name.
And down the road, we’ll see that the priest was a very courageous man.
I mean, he might wonder, why is he saying don't mention my name?
What is he afraid of?
How come he can't just go outside and say:
Here I'm a Muslim and invite everybody openly?
Why is he afraid, why is he keeping a secret?
But you will see that the priests was a very courageous man, but he was a wise man too.
The Associate of the king was blind.
And he came to this young man to cure him because now the young man has studied under the sorcerer.
So, now he is the expert people go to him.
So, when he went to the young man, the young man told him;
I cannot heal you, but Allah can heal you, Allah can do it,
and he healed the man.
So, the blind man who's now cured, went to the king, and the king told him; Who cured you.?
The man said: Allah.
The king said and do you have a god other than me?
The man said: Yes, Allah is my Lord and your Lord.
The king tortured, this friend of his,
and told him to disclose the name of the person, who taught him this.
And under the persecution, he gave up the name and said it is the young man or the boy.
Now, they brought in the boy, and they started to torture him.
And the boy under duress, and pain did give up the name of his teacher, the priest.
He could not sustain the pain and suffering that he was going through, so he disclosed the name
So, now they brought the priest and they told the priest, to give up his religion.
And he refused.
So, they brought a saw, and they place it on top of his head, and they cut him into two.
But he refused to give up his religion.
This is the courage that he had and this is the perseverance and the patience.
He gave up his life, he was tortured brutally.
But he never gave up his religion.
And now they're left with the boy.
So, the king ordered a group of his soldiers to carry this boy and throw him from the top of a cliff.
They carried the boy
and Subhaan Allah(سبحان الله), Allah was performing Karamaat(كرامات) on the hand of this boy.
Karamah(كرامة) is a miracle that would occur to a Non-Prophet.
And miracles happen to the Prophets.
That's the difference between Mujizza(معجزه) and Karamah(كرامة).
Mu'jizah(معجزة) happens to a Prophet and Karama(كرامه) happens to a person, who is not a Prophet,
but they are both supernatural events.
So, this boy made Dua(دُعَا) to Allah and said: O Allah
اِكْفِنِيْهِمْ بِمَا شِئْتْ
O Allah take care of them, the way you want,
I'm going to leave it, up to you
O Allah take care of them the way you want.
Allahسبحانه وتعالى made them reach, the top of the cliff, and then the cliff started to shake.
And all of the soldiers fell down, except he.
And now the boy is walking back and he entered into the palace of the king,
here I am again.
So, the king appointed another group of soldiers to take him, obviously soldiers are disposable with this king.
So, he appointed, the new group of soldiers to take him into a ship.
And when they reach into the deep waters, just throw him in the water.
So, they were on this boat, and he made the same Dua(دعا) again,
O Allah take care of them the way you want to.
The boat capsized, and they all drowned, except he,
he went back to safety.
So, he went to the king, and the king was ready to appoint a third group of soldiers to take him.
The boy told him wait,
you're not going to be able to kill me, unless you do what I tell you.
The King told him, what is it.?
The boy said, you tie me to a tree and you gather everyone
and you bring an arrow and you say: Bismillah(بسم الله),
the Lord of the boy,
then you will be able to kill me.
So, the boy told him the prescription of how to kill him.
And this is one of the many evidences given, for the justification of what is referred to as suicide bombings.
These are one of the evidences that are given that it is allowed.
Obviously there are restrictions on when it is allowed and where.
But the concept itself of a person giving up their life for Allahسبحانه وتعالى is a valid one,
based on this evidence, and many others.
Because he told the king, how it is possible to get rid of him.
If he didn't, he would have survived.
So, he basically told the king how to kill him.
But the boy did it for a noble cause.
What happened is the king followed the instructions and publicly said:
بِسْمِ الله رَبِّ الْغُلَامْ
In the Name of Allah, the Lord of the boy.
And the arrow hit him right in his head, and he immediately died.
But the result of that action was that everyone who attended became Muslim.
So, he did it for Da'wah(دعوة), he gave up his life,
so that everyone else would live.
Because the person is dead without Islam.
The advisors of the king told him what you're afraid of happened.
I mean in the whole purpose of killing this boy is, to get rid of this religion
and here we are stuck with our whole nation becoming Muslim.
Actually, in this situation Christian but it is Islam, it is the oneness of Allahسبحانه وتعالى.
Abu Nawaas(ابو نواس) instructed his soldiers to dig trenches,
after they dig trenches, they filled them with wood, and ignite them.
And anyone who refuses to give up their religion were forced them into the fire.
And they would bring loads of people and burn them alive.
And these are people who were holding firm to their faith and they didn't give up.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ says; there was a woman with her child in her arms, an infant
and she was walking towards the fire but then she hesitated,
imagine a mother carrying her infant.
So, she hesitated for a while and then Rasool Allah ﷺ says; but the infant spoke
and said: O mother, be patient because you are following the true path.
And she jumped in the fire.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says, there are three, who spoke in young age, this infant was one of them.
This story was recorded in Surat Ul Burooj(سورة البروج),
Surat Ul Buruj(سورة البروج) is referring to this story.
Surat Ul Buruj(سورة البروج) talks about the ones, who are burned,
As'haab Bil Ukhdood(أصحاب الأخدود) the people of the trench.
Now, even though these people were burned alive, and they ceased to exist, and the king won.
But Allahسبحانه وتعالى said that the Muslims were victorious.
Now, that's interesting.!
These people were killed, they did not establish any Khilafah(خِلَافَه), the king won.
How come, Allahسبحانه وتعالى said:
ذَٰلِكَ الْفَوْزُ الْكَبِيرُ
Allahسبحانه وتعالى did not only call it victory, Allah said that is the great victory.
Why?
How come these people lost in terms of worldly standards.?
Nevertheless, they're still called victorious.
Victory in their regard is the fact that they were able to hold firm on their faith until, the last moment, they never gave up.
That is victory entering Jannah(جنة) is victory.
So, even though they did not survive in Duniyah(دُنِيَّا),
but they were able to hold firm on their religion.
So, the father of Ammar Yasir(عمار ياسر) has won,
Sumayyah(سميعه) has won,
Hamza Bin Abdul Muttalib(حمزه بن عبدالمطلب), even though he was killed in the battlefield, he has won.
They have won in the eternal sense of winning,
even though they might have lost in a temporary battle in Duniyah(دُنِيَّا).
But the eternal battle they have won it, because they have entered Jannah(جنة), and Allahسبحانه وتعالى says:
ذَٰلِكَ الْفَوْزُ الْعَظِيْمْ
that is the great victory.
There is one person, who survived.
And this person traveled all the way to visit the Roman Emperor.
Now, he went to the Roman Empire because the Roman Empire was Christian,
even though these two people would be different Christian sects,
because by that time, the Romans might have already adopted the Trinity and the divinity of Eesa(عيسى).
But they still considered themselves to be followers of Eesa(عيسى).
So, he went to seek help from the Roman Emperor.
He said, this is what happened to us, we were persecuted, we were killed.
We need your help.!
The Roman Emperor said:
We are too far from Yemen.
But what, I could do, is send a message to the Najjashi(نجاشي),
the Nagus, of Abyssinia, who's also a Christian, and he can help you.
So, the Roman Emperor did that.
And they sent the message to An-Najjashi(ألنجاشي), in English, the Nagus.
And he sent an army led by a general named Ar-Rayyat(أرياط)
and Ar-Rayyat(أرياط) invaded Yemen, and fought with Du Nawaas(ذو نواس),
and Du Nawaas(ذو نواس), when he lost, he committed suicide.
It says that he was on his horse, and he just jumped in, to the Red Sea, he killed himself.
So, he lost, and now the Abyssinians were ruling over parts of Yemen.
And they did this as a revenge for the Christians, who were killed by the Jews of Yemen.
Ar-Rayyat(أرياط) ruled over Yemen for a while, he was very strict.
One of his army generals staged a revolt against him,
and the Abyssinians in Yemen, were divided now,
a group of them were with Ar-Rayyat(أرياط),
and the other group were with the new leader called Abraha(أبرهة).
And they were fighting,
Ar-Rayyat(أرياط) told Abraha(أبرهة); If we kill each other, the people of the land will take over.
So, how about we have a one-on-one fight, a man to man, Me and You.
Abraha(أبرهة) agreed.
But Abraha(أبرهة) made a secret agreement with some of his security guards.
That if you see me losing, jump in and help,
if you see me winning, leave me alone.
If you see that I'm losing come in.
So, you have all these people surrounding and Abraha(أبرهة) and Ar-Rayyat(أرياط) are in the middle,
now Ar-Rayyat(أرياط) was described as a tall and thin man,
and Abraha(أبرهة) was short and chubby.
So, Ar-Rayyat(أرياط) he was able to strike Abraha(أبرهة) from the top and he chopped off his nose.
So, Abraha(أبرهة) was called Abraha Al-Ushrum (أبرهة ألأشرم),
Ashram(اشرم), means his nose is chopped off.
When that happened, the bodyguards jumped in and they killed Ar-Rayyat(أرياط).
He betrayed obviously this is against rules,
but the issue is over now, Ar-Rayyat(أرياط) is dead.
Abraha(أبرهة) now took over and he was the one, ruling over Yemen.
Abraha(أبرهة) wanted to change the religion of the people,
and forced them to become Christian.
And since the Arabs were attached to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه),
he decided to build a counterpart to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) in Sana'a(صنعاء), in Yemen.
So, he built a huge Cathedral called Al-Kulais(ألكليس).
And this was described as a wonderful piece of art and huge, and great.
I mean, he had access of wealth from Abyssinia.
So, they built this huge Cathedral in Sana'a(صنعاء) to compete with Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
Now, one man didn't like this idea.
What he did was a bit crude.
He went into Al-Kullais(ألكليس), and he defecated
and then not only that, he took it and he spread it all over the walls
stool, imagine stool all over the walls, and he ran away.
Abraha(أبرهة) was furious.
What is this, what is this guy doing?
He was so angry, he decided that he must get rid of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
I mean, I'm going to put an end to this, and destroy Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه),
he mobilized an army and the march towards Makkah.
There was some resistance along the way, one of the chiefs of a tribe,
his name is Nufail(نفيل).
He put up some resistance, but he was defeated,
I mean Abraha(أبرهة) is a huge powerful army.
And they captured Nufail(نفيل), they captured him as a prisoner of war.
When Abraha(أبرهة) reached to At-Taef(ألطائف),
the people of At-Taef(ألطائف) assisted Abraha(أبرهة),
and one of them offered to be a guide for Abraha(أبرهة), for the rest of the journey.
And this man his name is Abu Raghal(أبو رغال).
So, Abu Raghal(أبو رغال), he went out to the army.
But then immediately when they got out of At-Taef(ألطائف) he died.
So, then the Arabs were so upset with Abu Raghal(أبو رغال)
they built in the place of his death a monument that they would stone, because of his betrayal.
Anyway, Abraha(أبرهة) made it to the outskirts of Makkah
And there were some shepherds with camels, grazing
He took possession of them.
200 of these camels belonged to Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) the grandfather of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) came out of Makkah to meet with Abraha(أبرهة).
Now obviously, Abraha(أبرهة), you can't just walk in and meet him, he was such a important figure.
So, Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) has to have some connections to get in,
Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) happened to be a friend of Nufail(نفيل).
Who was captured as a prisoner of war.
Nufail(نفيل) was carried with the army.
And he befriended, he became friends with a man called Unais(أنيس).
And this man Unais(أنيس) was such an important person in the army.
He was a pilot of the elephant, which was their most valuable, piece of equipment.
So, Nufail(نفيل) now is very well connected, he knows Unais(أنيس).
So, Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) came to Nufail(نفيل) and told him; I want to meet with Abraha(أبرهة).
Nufail(نفيل) told him: Sure, I'll arrange for your a meeting through my friend Unais(أنيس).
So, Unais(أنيس) arranged the meeting with Abraha(أبرهة).
And Abraha(أبرهة) welcomed Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب).
Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) walked in,
and Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) was described as being a man with a very strong presence in all.
I mean, by just seeing him, a person becomes impressed.
So, when Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) came in,
Abraha(أبرهة) held him, in a high esteem, even though they didn't even talk yet.
Now, the rules were that Abraha(أبرهة) sits on a very high throne.
And people sit under his feet.
So, you come and have a meeting with Abraha(أبرهة), you are sitting under his feet.
Abraha(أبرهة), when he saw Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب), he didn't feel comfortable at all,
having Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) sit under him.
But he cannot also allow Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) to sit with him,
on the throne because nobody should sit on the throne, except he.
So, what he did is he came down from his throne
and sat with Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) on the floor.
And he told Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب),
he told the interpreter to ask Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب), what does he need?
Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) straight ahead, told the interpreter.
Abraha(أبرهة) has taken possession of 200 of my camels, I want them back.
Abraha(أبرهة) responded and said: When I saw you, I had so much respect for you, but I've lost it all.
I'm coming to destroy your honor and the honor of your father's,
I am coming to destroy the center of your livelihood,
I am coming to destroy Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه), and you're asking me about camels.
Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) responded and said: I am the owner of the camels.
So, I'm responsible for them.
And this house belongs to Allah and Allah will protect it.
I'm here to ask for what is under my authority, my responsibility.
The house belongs to Allah, Allah will take care of it and Allah will protect it.
Abraha(أبرهة) said give him back his camels.
Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) went back to Makkah and he told the people of Makkah,
do not fight, withdraw out of Makkah,
Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) gave them clear instructions.
We're not going to fight Abraha(أبرهة), we're going to leave.
And they all went up to the mountains.
And Abdul Muttalib(عبد المطلب) was the last one to leave and before he left,
he was hanging on the clothes of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) or the handle of the door of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
And he was praying to Allahسبحانه وتعالى to protect His house, and then he left.
So, all of them have evacuated, everyone evacuated Makkah.
And Abraha(أبرهة) now issued his instructions to march forth.
But the elephant refused to move.
They turned the elephant to a different direction, he would stand up running.
They turned him towards the direction of Makkah, he would sit down.
How come, a miracle from Allah but it is said in the story,
that this man Nufail(نفيل), who was a prisoner of war, he released himself from his chains,
and he jumped to the ear of the elephant and he said to the elephant,
this is the house of Allah, do not attack it and he ran away.
But whether that was the reason or not, the elephant refused to march in the direction of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه),
and they would beat it, they started poking it with their spears,
and the elephant was bleeding, it refused to move.
Eventually, they decided they're gonna have to leave the elephant
and they made their move forward.
Allahسبحانه وتعالى sent on them an army.
No, one knows the soldiers of Allah, anything can be a soldier of Allah.
Water which is the source of life can be a soldier of Allah.
Water is, what killed the tyrant, Firoun(فرعون).
Wind is a soldier of Allah,
وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ ۚ
Allahسبحانه وتعالى says; No one knows His soldiers but He.
So, Allahسبحانه وتعالى sent an army of birds,
every birds carrying with it, missiles, that were sent on the army of Abraha(أبرهة)
and destroy them all, they were all killed.
And this event was recorded in Surat Tul Feel(سورةالفيل).
أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ فَعَلَ رَبُّكَ بِأَصْحَابِ الْفِيلِ۝أَلَمْ يَجْعَلْ كَيْدَهُمْ فِي تَضْلِيلٍ۝
وَأَرْسَلَ عَلَيْهِمْ طَيْرًا أَبَابِيلَ۝ تَرْمِيهِمْ بِحِجَارَةٍ مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ۝
فَجَعَلَهُمْ كَعَصْفٍ مَأْكُولٍ۝
These are the events up to the year, in which Rasool Allah ﷺ was born.
Rasool Allah ﷺ was born in the year of the elephant,
in the same year, Rasool Allah ﷺ was born.
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ